ADAM VIGEANT

UX DESIGNER | DESIGN THINKER



CONTACT

- 603-321-3749

AdamVigeantUX@gmail.com



www.AVigeant.com



linkedin.com/in/adamvigeant/

UX SKILLS

- Design Thinking
- User-Centered Design (UCD)
- UI & Visual Design
- Wireframes & Prototyping
- User Experience Research
- Design Personas
- User Flows
- Journey Maps
- Information Architecture (IA)
- Usability Testing
- Interaction Design

TOOLS

- Adobe Creative Cloud (CC)
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe XD
- Axure
- Balsamiq
- Figma
- InVision
- Sketch
- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript

PROFILE

User Experience Designer with a passion to solve challenging problems. A capable and empathetic mediator between client, business, and development teams, with creative problemsolving abilities rooted in Design Thinking.

Experienced in UX best practices with awareness of the psychological and human factors that influence design, Adam is a well-rounded, collaborative, and effective teammate with over 10 years experience in graphic and interaction design.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UX & VISUAL DESIGNER

Adam Vigeant Design | Remote, Ohio | 2011-Present

- Designed over 10 unique brand identities in addition to numerous web, graphic, and informational deliverables.
- Collaborated with clients to implement design solutions that meet specific user needs and vision.
- Implemented effective communication, time-management, and organizational strategy to ensure high-quality work.
- Communicated with businesses and translated complex problems into understandable action-steps.
- Improved effectiveness of designs through researching and implementing UX tools, techniques, and best practices for optimum usability and accessibility.

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Powell Prints | Hilliard, Ohio | 2015-2021

- Curated over 300 visual designs for customers, preserving brand guidelines and budget/time constraints.
- Balanced needs of management, product production, and customers to produce effective design solutions.
- Utilized Design Thinking to develop creative solutions to address business and client needs.
- Advised management and production teams on current design trends and implemented workflow improvements.
- Facilitated client meetings to identify needs, build relational equity, and establish project parameters.

EDUCATION

UX Design & Frontend Development Certifications

CareerFoundry | 2020-2021

Bachelor of Science (BS)—Media Design

Indiana Wesleyan University | 2009-2013